<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Startups | Ed K]]></title>
  <link href="http://outerloop.github.io/blog/categories/startups/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://outerloop.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-02T21:45:10-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://outerloop.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[outerloop]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[outerloop@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Startup Weekend Toronto EDU: Library Edition 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://outerloop.github.io/blog/2014/04/02/startup-weekend-toronto-edu-library-edition-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-02T20:55:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://outerloop.github.io/blog/2014/04/02/startup-weekend-toronto-edu-library-edition-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to everyone who completed the library survey. If you&rsquo;re curious how your feedback was used, last weekend I participated in Startup Weekend Toronto EDU: Library Edition. Over the weekend, our impromptu team took an elevator pitch (SignWave) through business model development, market validation, prototype design and creation, and a final pitch to a panel of industry judges.</p>

<p>SignWave is an interactive digital sign for libraries. We identified two problems &mdash; students who have difficulty navigating academic libraries and librarians who are constantly answering directional queries. Our solution is to improve the current static signage by allowing library patrons to interact with large format signs via gestures to get directions and/or information, liberating librarians from answering repetitive queries.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a crowded market for digital signs so we cater to the limited budgets of libraries by offering a free/low-cost solution using off-the-shelf parts and our open source signage software. Our company generates revenue by offering &ldquo;Signs-as-a-Service&rdquo; (i.e. hosting and support) and professional services (e.g. consulting, training).</p>

<p>You can play with the demo and flip through our deck here:
<a href="http://signwave.github.io/">http://signwave.github.io</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
